Guide to the Vassar College Miscellaneous Campus Organizations Records, 1882-1997
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Vassar College Miscellaneous Campus Organizations Records
1882-1997
Vassar College
0.6 cubic feet (2 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Meeting minutes, constitutions, clippings, scrapbooks, and other material related to a variety of student clubs and campus organizations at Vassar College.
Historical Note
Vassar College was founded in 1861 and opened its doors in 1865.
Scope and Content Note
Meeting minutes, constitutions, clippings, scrapbooks, and other material related to a variety of student clubs and campus organizations at Vassar College.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar Students' Association
.
Subject Headings
Organizations:
Vassar College. Association of College Specials; Vassar College. Debate Society; Vassar College. Employees Golf Association; Vassar College. Latin Journal Club; Vassar College. Microscopical Club; Vassar College. Night Owls; Vassar College. Qui Vive Club; Vassar College. Steadfast Club; Vassar College--Societies and clubs; Vassar College--Students
Subjects:
Debates and debating; Employee affinity groups; Student organizations--United States; Women college students--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Women--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie--Societies and clubs
Document Types:
Clippings; Correspondence; Minutes (administrative records); Scrapbooks
VCL Categories:
Vassar College Campus Organizations
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, November 2023.
Acquisition Information
Records of the Microscopical Club were the gift of Abigail F. Goodsell, March 1890.
Records of the Night Owls were the gift of Mikie Benedict (VC 1997), December 2009. [A2009-049]
Origin of other records is unknown, although they were likely donated by the organization of origin.
Container List
- Qui Vive Club (1882-1917)
  The Qui Vive Club was established by the Sophomore class in the Spring of 1882 as a club for the discussion of current, historical, and literary topics. Minnie Cumnock Blodgett served as its first president. Qui Vive regularly invited lecturers to speak on various topics and hosted debates on a variety of issues. They often debated with Vassar's other debate club, the politically-oriented T & M Club. These two clubs were abolished in the Spring of 1917 and replaced by the new Vassar Debating Society, later called the Vassar College Debate Society.
  - Records, 1882-1892; (1 volume) (Folder 1.1)
- Microscopical Club (1887-1890)
  Established in 1887, the Vassar College Microscopical Club's stated objective was "to unite its members in practical microscopical work." Consisting of both students and faculty, the club met monthly, often in the biology laboratory, to research and examine scientific specimens such as water samples from the Vassar lake, starfish, and Bryozoa. It was disbanded after only 2 years, in February of 1890.
  - Constitution, 1887 (Folder 1.2)
  - Minutes, 1887-1890; (1 volume) (Folder 1.3)
- Association of Collegiate Specials (1888-)
  The Association of Collegiate Specials, established in 1888, was a student government and collective-bargaining organization for Vassar College's Speciality students, who were not members of a graduating class.
  - Constitution and minutes, 1888-1894; (1 volume) (Folder 1.4)
- Steadfast Club (1890-1891)
  Established in 1890, the short-lived Steadfast Club was organized to benefit Vassar College employees through classes in reading, penmanship, arithmetic, dress-making, and shorthand. It included faculty, employees, and students in its membership.
  - Minutes, 1890-1891; (1 volume) (Folder 1.5)
- Latin Journal Club (1902-)
  A faculty literature club established in 1902, whose original goal was to keep faculty informed regarding current literature and publications in the area of Classical Studies. Over the years, meetings of the club expanded from reviewing academic journals to include papers, book reviews, play readings, biographies of classical scholars, and reports of classical adventures abroad. The club was renamed as the Classical Journal Club at some point after 1935.
  - Minutes, 1902-1935; (1 volume) (Folder 1.6)
- Vassar College Debate Society (1917-Present)
  Vassar College's longest-running debate club, the Debate Society replaced several earlier clubs, including the Qui Vive Club and the T & M Club, in the Spring of 1917.
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1922-1924 (Folder 1.7)
- Employees Golf Association
  An employee and faculty golf club active primarily during the 1930s.
  - Scrapbook, 1939; (1 volume) (Box 2)
- Night Owls (1946-Present)
  Begun as the Class of 1947 musical octet, the Night Owls a capella group recruited new members from other graduating classes and soon became a fixture among Vassar College's musical groups. As of 2023, they are the college's oldest and longest-running musical group.
  - Correspondence, clippings, and business manager manual, 1996-1997 (Folder 1.8)